Paige Williams

Front end developer & cartographer



Portland, OR



paw145@humboldt.edu



/paigewilliams



/paige--williams

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, HTML/CSS, SQL

Frameworks / Libraries:

Angular, React, Node.js, Gatsby, Rails, Sinatra

Database: Postgres, GraphQL, Firebase

Testing: Jasmine, Karma, Jest, Rspec

GIS: ArcMap 10.x, QGIS, Leaflet

Versioning: Git

Design: Illustrator, InDesign

I am passionate about serving people and the planet through tech. I enjoy problem solving and working towards innovative solutions. I am invigorated by exploring the different ways that tech, data, and civic engagement intersect.

Projects

Message Hunter / Ruby on Rails, JS, Google Maps API, Postgres With a small group, I created a geocaching meets social media app where users can leave geolocated messages for each other. I implemented the map component and integrated the database of messages to populate in the map.

Food Savor / Angular 5, TypeScript, Firebase, Google Auth, HTML/CSS A small group and I created an app to find recipes that use near-expiring ingredients. I worked on all parts of the stack, from querying the API, database schema design, and styling the UI.

Experience

Pastaworks / Wine Assistant and Floor Supervisor

MARCH 2017 - JANUARY 2019

- Create maps for the monthly wine club that follow design guidelines
- Assign daily tasks and prioritize customer service and productivity

Metro / Regional Planning Intern

SEPTEMBER 2016 - MARCH 2017

- Assist the Regional Planning department with GIS and cartographic applications
- Create static and interactive maps for the Regional Snapshots
- Build and maintain the Active Transportation Plan projects database

Education

Epicodus / Certificate in Web Development

ANTICIPATED MAY 2019, PORTLAND, OR

Learned Ruby, JavaScript and React through pair-programming. The environment was similar to an office where we work for 40+ hours a week and solve problems as a team.

Humboldt State University / B. A. Environmental Studies with a minor in Geospatial Studies, Cum Laude

SEPTEMBER 2012 - MAY 2016, ARCATA, CA